

Muhasin Uddin Mahmud Full-Stack Developer | Usability Engineer

ABOUT ME

Experienced software developer and UX/UI designer with strong skills in web programming languages, committed to building user-friendly and effective digital solutions.

للله January 16, 1989 in Madaripur, Bangladesh

mahmudmuhasin@gmail.com



+49 15774134901

Eisenstraße 56 40227 Düsseldorf, Germany

DRIVING LICENSE

LANGUAGES

Englisch: Expert

Deutsch: Intermediate

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2022 - present

SOFTWARE AND WEB DEVELOPMENT TRAINER Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf, Deutschland

Teach full stack Web Development with a focus on the MERN stack, oversee student projects, and offer mentorship to support their progression in web development.

January 2021 - present

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST (PART TIME)

Healthy Smile Dental Care

Dhaka, Bangladesh

I developed and have been maintaining the official website for Healthy Smile Dhaka, a renowned dental clinic in Bangladesh, since 2021.

February 2022 - June 2022

JUNIOR TEST AUTOMATION ENGINEER / WEB DEVELOPMENT

Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf, Deutschland

Developed automation code to test students' exercises besides teaching.

June 2021 - February 2022

ASSISTANT TRAINER WEB DEVELOPMENT

Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf, Deutschland

Assisted in teaching web development courses and provided support for student projects.

Conducted workshops and coding sessions.

Supported the teaching team in delivering full-stack web development curriculum.

May 2012 - April 2013

ASSOCIATE RESEARCHER

University Grant Commission of Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Participated in a research project entitled 'Mental Health in Relation to Environmental Noise in High-Rise Buildings.'

EDUCATION

2020 - 2021

WEITERBILDUNG IN SOFTWARE UND WEB DEVELOPMENT

Digital Career Institute (DCI), Full-stack Web Development

Düsseldorf, Deutschland

Completed an intensive 14-month course aimed at improving programming skills through numerous projects. Specialized in the MERN stack, with a focus on software methodologies, developing individual

projects, and deployment techniques.

2018 - 2020

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.SC)

Hochschule Rhein-Waal, Usability Engineering

Kamp-Lintfort, Deutschland

Master thesis: The correlation between changes in mental representation structures and corresponding gaze behavior.

2020 - 2020

ORIENTIERUNG IN TECHNISCHEN BERUFEN

Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf, Deutschland

Four-week orientation course in the digital economy.

2007 - 2012

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.SC)

Jagannath University, Psychology

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SKILLS



TRAIN THE TRAINER

- Introduction to pedagogical techniques and educational theory
- Introduction of methods to assist in effective lesson design
- Exercises designed to improve lecturing skills and knowledge transfer

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhasin-uddin-mahmud-5b6639164/

GITHUB

https://github.com/muhasin-m

CV - Muhasin Uddin Mahmud 2/2